Our name is Ouroboros.
我々の名はウロボロス
If you want to save your citizens, release him right away.
市民を救いたければ
速やかに解放していただきたい
Our comrade, Jake Martinez...
我が同胞 ジェイク・マルチネスを
Jake...
ジェイク…
うっ…
I look forward to hearing a favorable response.
それでは皆様
前向きな回答を期待しておりますわ
gokigen yo doukashitan darou?
How are you? Is something wrong?
ごきげんよう　どうかしたんだろ？
kao wo mireba isshun de wakaru yo
I can tell just by looking at you.
顔を見れば一瞬でわかるよ
senrigan senrigan? messou nai desu
Am I psychic? Of course not.
千里眼千里眼？
めっそうないです
taikutsu GIRL megumaretai no kai
Bored girl, do you want to find happiness?
退屈ガール　恵まれたいのかい
hantei wa shingi no renzoku de
Let's think it through and decide.
判定は審議の連続で
VENUS SUSTAIN
Venus Sustain.
ヴィーナスサステイン
odoru machinami
The city dances.
踊る街並み
PERFECTLY EUPHORIA
Perfectly, Euphoria!
Perfectly Euphoria！
nandemo nai youna kotoba de naitari suru shi
I end up crying over the smallest things.
何でもないような
言葉で泣いたりするし
hora bokutachi nante
Come on, our
ほら　僕達なんて
zentei no nai
temporary passion
juubun tekido ni
lives are
十分適度に
zentei no nai
a temporary passion
DRAMATIC sa
reasonably dramatic.
ドラマチックさ
saikou no wa
the best passion
karuku SUPER STAR
We're almost like super stars!
軽くスーパースター
ORION wo nazoru konna fukai yoru
Looking up at Orion late at night.
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜
tsunagaretai hanasaretai
I want to connect. I want to be free.
つながりたい　離されたい
tsumari hanshinhangi acchi kocchi
Basically, I'm not sure and can't decide.
つまり半信半疑あっちこっち
shin mirai wo negau kuuzenzetsugo no
I pray for a new future. The greatest one yet.
新未来を願う 空前絶後の
kotoba ga moshi, moshi tsumugeru nara jikan ga tomaru yo
If I could spin words, time would stop.
言葉がもし もし紡げるなら
時間が止まるよ
koko de owaru hazu ga nai no ni
"There's no way it can end here."
「ココデオワルハズガナイノニ」
なんとか市民を避難させることは
できないのか？
Isn't there some way we could evacuate the citizens?
ダウンタウン地区という手がある
There's always the Downtown Area!
あそこは何も手を出されていない
That place hasn't been hit.
そうだ そこだ！
Yes, that's right!
そんなことは すでに
市民も考えていますよ
People have already thought of that.
どちらにせよ この都市は
In any case, this city is built into three separate levels
シュテルンメダイユ地区中心に
三層で建設されています
with Stern Medaille Area at its center.
その芯が落ちれば すべて雪崩的に
Should its foundation collapse, everything will go down with it.
市民の命が握られてしまってる以上
They are holding citizens hostage.
We cannot do anything reckless.
うかつな手出しは できませんね
では テロに屈しろというのかね？
Are you saying we should give in to terrorists?
そんな醜態さらすわけには いかん！
We can't do anything that shameful!
まさか こんな事態になるとは…
I never expected this to happen.
テロはヒーローが なんとか
してくれるんじゃなかったんですか？
I thought you said the Heroes would handle this!
アニエスさん 僕たちに
何かできることはない？
Ms. Agnes, isn't there anything we can do?
ええ 今わね
Not right now.
こんな状況で
指をくわえて見てろって言うの？
Are you telling us to just sit here and watch?!
しかし 実際
どうにも手出しはできないしなぁ…
But there really is nothing we can do.
いや 我々にしかできないことは
きっとある
No, I'm sure there is something that only we can do.
ただ 今は それが待機ということだ
And right now, that is to stand by and wait.
お前の気持ちはわかる
I understand how you feel.
けど 今は市民の命がかかってる
But right now, people's lives are at stake.
そんなこと わかってますよ！
I know that!
おお…
おい おい　こんなときに仲間割れかよ
Come on, guys. This is no time for arguing.
ケンカなんかしてる場合じゃ
ないんじゃない？
We don't have time for this.
んっ…
なんだよ あいつ
What's his problem?
んん…
わりい わりい
Sorry about that, guys! It looks like I got on his nerves.
なんか俺 怒らせちゃったみたいで
なに言ったんだ？
What did you say to him?
いや　俺のヒーロー名の由来を
教えただけなんだけど…
Well, I told him how I got my code name.
はっ？
Huh?
虎徹の“こ”が“虎”だから
The "Ko" in "Kotetsu" means "Tiger,"
ワイルドタイガーなんだぜって
hence the name "Wild Tiger." Get it?
はあ？
Say what?
今 そんな話をしてる場合かよ！
This is no time for jokes like that!
そりゃ
No wonder he got so upset.
“そんなことわかってますよ！”
って言いますね
だよな
Yeah. I'm going to go apologize to him.
ちと謝ってくるわ
あそこまで無神経な男だと思わなかった
I never knew he was that insensitive.
あんた あれ 本気にしてんの？
You actually believed what he just said?
えっ…
おい バニー！
Hey, Bunny!
どこ行くんだよ？
Where are you going? Wait up!
待ってって おい！
すみません
I'm sorry. I lost it back there, when you were just trying to help.
心配していただいたのに
つい感情的になってしまって
チッ！
やっと たどり着いたのに…
Just when I thought I finally found him!
緊急事態よ
We have an emergency!
何だって？　よく聞こえない
What? I can't hear you!
The powered exosuits destroyed
イーストブロンズの支柱が
パワードスーツに破壊されたわ
one of the support columns in East Bronze.
スカイハイ ブルーローズ
すぐに現場に向かって
Sky High, Blue Rose, head to the scene right away!
I don't mind going there, but what should we do?
行くのはいいけど 何をすればいいの？
Ignore the powered exosuits.
パワードスーツは放っておいて
人命救助とパニック回避を最優先
Saving people and preventing widespread panic
are your top priorities!
ええ
I'm going too, Agnes!
俺も行くぞ アニエス
Don't do anything without permission!
勝手な行動はしないで！
おお…
Why not?!
なんでだよ？
まだ次があるかもしれない
There might be another attack.
ほかのヒーローは待機
I want the other Heroes to be on standby!
次がある前に なんとかしろよ！
We should do something before there is another attack!
上の連中は 何 モタモタやってんだ！
What's taking the higher-ups so long to make a decision?!
もはやシュテルンビルトは
壊滅間近と言えるこの状況
With Stern Bild standing on the brink of destruction,
we can only hope for the mayor
一刻も早い市長の決断が待ち望まれます
to make a decision as soon as possible.
確かに 次なんて言ってられないわね
He's right.
We shouldn't stand here just thinking about the next attack.
んっ…
あの〜 誠意ある回答を
期待したんですけれど
You know...
We've been waiting to hear some good news.
まだ本気だって
わかってもらえませんの？
Still not convinced that we're serious?
うっ…
次は１時間後の11時に
Our next attack will be in an hour, at eleven o'clock.
場所は そうね…
We'll decide where by rolling a die.
ダイスを振って決めようかしら
んん…
I can't wait any longer. Let's go, Bunny!
もう我慢できねえ
行くぞ バニー！
ちょっとワイルドタイガー！
命令に背くつもり？
Hey, Wild Tiger!
Are you going to disobey orders?
Another support column is going to be destroyed.
また支柱が破壊される
いや まだブラフの可能性もある
They could be bluffing!
しかし すでに
町が傾き始めているんですぞ
But the city is already beginning to tilt!
もはや悠長なことを言っていられる
事態ではないでしょう
We can't drag this out any longer.
We need you to make a decision, Mr. Mayor.
やはり市長 ご決断を
えっ？
Huh?
We have no choice.
やむを得ません
ジェイクの解放を
Please have Jake released.
ちょっ… ちょっと待ってくださいよ
Wait just a second.
そうやって責任だけを私に
Don't make me take all the responsibility.
責任問題で済むなら
私が いくらでも取りましょう
I'll take full responsibility,
if that's what it'll take to get through this.
ただ決定権は市長にしかないんです
But only you can make the final decision!
しかし 万が一にでも問題が起きたら…
But if by any chance things go wrong...
ご指示どおり
I have deployed Sky High and Blue Rose
現場には スカイハイと
ブルーローズを派遣しました
to the scene as you commanded.
ですが １つだけ問題が…
But there's just one problem.
いったい何を迷ってるんだよ？
Why are you hesitating?
市民の命を守ることが
最優先じゃねえのか？
Isn't saving people's lives your top priority?
きっ… 君はアポロンの？
You're Apollon's...
ああ…
ジェイクたちは
あとで必ず捕まえますから
We'll catch Jake and his gang later on.
そのための俺たちヒーローでしょうが！
That's what we Heroes are here for!
But...
しかし…
あんたらは いつだって そうだ！
What is wrong with all of you?!
All you guys care about is that thing of yours...
いっつも… 自分の…
あればっかり考えてて
あれ？
What thing?
ああ なんだっけ… あの…
What was it? Umm... Protect...
守る感じの…
You mean self-interests?
保身ですか？
そう それ！
Yeah, that's it!
ああ… あっ！
Oh.
何が大事かを考えてみろよ
Think about what's important.
あんたらにだって
この町に家族や友達いるんだろ？
You have family and friends in this city too, right?
あっ…
Then make a decision right now!
だったら すぐに決断しろよ
とりあえず今は
自分の あ… あれは忘れてさ
Anyway, for now forget about your own whatchamacallits.
保身
Self-interests.
That's right!
そう！
彼の言い分
ビシッと決まらなかったですけど
Though he wasn't very clear, I think he's got a point.
一応 正論だと思います
フッ…
確かに そいつの言うとおりだ
He's absolutely right.
おお…
ただ 捕まったりはしないけどな
Except that he won't be able to catch us.
ん… あっ…
いいかげん
こっちも待ちくたびれちまってねぇ
We got tired of waiting. I'm here to work out the details.
ぜひ具体的な話でもしようかと
Are you a member of Ouroboros?
きっ… 君はウロボロスの…
んん…
あっ…
俺はハンス・チャックマン
I'm Hans Chuckman.
交渉役として遣わされて…
I was sent to negotiate.
てめえ どの面 下げて来やがった！
You bastard! You have some nerve to show up like this!
おい おい
俺に手を出す意味がわかってんのか？
Calm down.
Do you know what'll happen if you attack me?
That's right. People's lives are at stake.
おっ！　そうだよ 君
市民の命が…
すみません
Sorry. People's lives are top priority! Mr. Mayor, sir!
そういや〜 市民の命が最優先でした
市長
あっ…
で どうなったんだ？
So what did all of you big shots decide on?
お偉方が がん首 揃えてよ
あっ？
あっ… ええっと…
Oh, umm...
Well, in order to ensure the safety of the people,
では 市民の安全のため
先にパワードスーツの撤退を…
we'd like you to withdraw your powered exosuits.
あっ？　ふざけてんじゃねえぞ！
Huh? You've got to be kidding me!
まだ状況がわかってないのか？
Do you still not understand the situation?!
No, but the power...
いっ… いや〜
だが パッ… パワー…
“パッ… パワー…”じゃ ねえんだよ
Don't give me that crap.
俺はイエスのひと言だけを
聞きにきてんだ
I just came to hear you say, "yes."
All right. We'll think about it once more.
わかった では もう一度 検討して…
引き延ばしてもムダだぜ
It's no use trying to buy yourself time.
If I don't come back before the time's up...
もし時間内に俺が戻らなかったときは
ドカーン！
Kaboom.
しっ… 市民の皆様に
ご報告 申し上げます
Citizens, I have an announcement.
皆様の命と安全を最優先に考えた結果
Your lives and safety are our top priority, and therefore,
we have concluded that we cannot allow any more casualties.
これ以上 犠牲を増やすことは
できないという結論に達し
彼らの要求を全面的に受け入れ
We have decided that we will give in to their demands
ジェイクの解放を決定いたしました
and release Jake Martinez.
じゃあ 助かるってことか
Does that mean we're saved?
フフッ…
Jake? I thought you were in here for life?
ジェイク お前 終身刑だったはずじゃ
Want to know why I'm on this side?
なんで俺が こっち側にいるのかって？
そりゃ 簡単な話だ
It's simple.
Because I'm Jake, and you're not.
俺がジェイクで
お前がジェイクじゃねえからだろ〜
あっ…
ハッハッ　そう そう
Oh yeah. You can still call me "Jake" the next time we meet.
今度 会ったときも
呼び捨てで かまわねえよ〜
Though, there isn't going to be a next time.
まあ 二度と会えねえけど
うわ〜！
やっぱり お前の仕業だったか〜
I figured this was your doing, Kriem!
クリーム
I'm sorry for making you wait for such a long time, Mister Jake.
長い間お待たせして
申し訳ありませんでした
ジェイク様
一体どうやって やったんだ？
How did you do it?
えっ？
それは ご想像に お任せいたしますわ
I'll leave that to your imagination.
秘密か〜
A secret, eh? I love secrets!
いいね 秘密
ミステリアスな女は好きだぜ
And I love women with secrets.
Jake has been released just now!
今 ジェイクが解放されたもようです
壊滅の危機は去ったのでしょうか？
Has the possible destruction been averted?
今は我慢の時ってやつだなあ
Right now, we need to be patient.
Once the people are safe, we'll make our move.
市民の安全が確保されたあと
俺たちが動くんだ
この作戦
うまく いけばいいけどなあ…
I hope this plan goes well.
I know, right? Is that poor boy going to be okay?
ほんと あの子 大丈夫かしら
くうっ…
As always, this city is a dump.
相変わらず掃きだめみてえな町だな〜
おっ…
祝杯だよ
How about a toast?
I'm piloting right now.
今は操縦中なので
You're so serious!
真面目だな〜
Do you think you can get away with doing this to me?
俺に こんなことして
タダで済むと思ってるのか？
この町が沈むんだぞ
This city is going to sink!
We know that. Which is where I come in.
ええ だからこそ僕の出番なんです
Huh?
はあ？
あっ…
I'm sorry for asking you to do this.
無理を言って すみません
But I figured your powers could pull this off.
ただ あなたの能力ならと思って
はっ…
If things go wrong, your life will be in danger.
もちろん 一歩 間違えれば
命の危険もあります　なので…
So I won't force you to do this...
やります
I'll do it! I am a Hero, after all.
これでも僕はヒーローですから
あっ…
This is something only I can do, right? So I'll do it!
それに これは
僕にしかできないことですよね
やります！
Hey, Origami.
おい 折紙！
You forgot this.
忘れもんだ
Oh...
あっ…
Thanks.
あっ… すみません
If something happens, make sure you contact us right away.
何かあったら すぐ連絡しろ
We'll head on over at any time.
いつでも俺たちが駆けつけるからな
Right!
はい
Our future now rests on your shoulders.
今や すべては君に託すしかないんだ
We're counting on you, Origami Cyclone!
頼むぞ
折紙サイクロン
Yes, sir!
はい
By the way, Kriem... Who is this guy?
ところでクリーム
こいつは誰なんだ？
Hans Chuckman.
ハンス・チャックマン
非ＮＥＸＴですが
我々の思想に賛同した男です
He's not a NEXT, but he believes in our cause.
ただの人間か〜
A regular human, huh? That explains why he's so boring.
どおりで つまんない訳だ
He wants to see our utopian nation that is controlled by NEXT—
私たちの理想郷であるＮＥＸＴが
統べる国
ジェイク様の統治する世界を見たいと
a world ruled by you.
Oh? Does that mean you aspire to become a NEXT some day?
へえ〜
じゃあ お前
いつかＮＥＸＴになるのが夢ってか？
Huh?
あっ…
It's impossible.
そんのは無理だ 無理
なっ クリーム？
Right, Kriem?
Yes. We NEXT are God's chosen ones.
ええ 神によって選ばれた者
それが私たちＮＥＸＴ
Chuckman!
チャックマン
Yes, ma'am!
あっ… はい
Mister Jake has been released as planned,
予定どおり
ジェイク様が釈放されたので
so prepare to release the hostages.
人質解放の準備を
Yes, ma'am.
はい
Wait!
待てよ！
んん…
Hostages? What's that about?
人質って 何 それ？
Has anything happened?
状況に変わりないか？
Everything's the same. They aren't doing anything special.
依然として目立った動きはありません
I see.
そうか…
When are they going to pull out their forces?!
撤退は まだか？
一体いつになるんだ？
There's no need to panic.
あっ… 焦ることはありませんよ
It's only been half-an-hour since his release.
まだ解放から30分しか
たっていません
Maybe they're just sight-seeing for now.
今は ゆっくり
観光でもしてるんじゃないかな…
It's all right. Our plan is going well.
大丈夫
策は万全です
For now, let's wait for Origami Cyclone to contact us.
今は折紙サイクロンからの連絡を
待ちましょう
Is it really all right? What would happen if he...
本当に大丈夫ですかねえ
万一 彼が…
As long as he's alive,
彼が生きているかぎりは
バイタルサインが発信され続けますよ
we'll continue to get readings of his vital signs.
But if this green turns red...
ただ この緑が赤に変わったときは…
んん…
Hey! What's going on?
おい どうなってるんだ？
We released him as promised!
約束どおり 解放しただろう！
Don't ask me. I don't know.
そんなこと言われたって
俺だってわからねえよ
We need to trust Origami and wait.
今は折紙さんを信じて待とうよ
クッ！
うう…
What does Ouroboros want to do?! Answer me!
そもそも 貴様らウロボロスの目的は
何なんだ？
答えろ！
あっ… ああ…
んっ！
Stop it, Bunny. That's going too far!
もう やめとけ バニー
やりすぎだ
ああ…
ぐわっ…
I'm going to cool off for a bit.
少し頭を冷やしてきます
ブハッ ゴホッ…
They probably caught on to your shoddy plan.
お前らのこそくな作戦が
バレたんじゃねえのか？
Please leave me alone.
放っておいてください
あぁ…
はあ…
How long do you plan on standing there?
いつまで いるつもりですか？
That's none of your business. Please leave me alone.
俺の勝手だろう
放っておいてください
自分でも情けないことくらい
わかってますから
I know I'm being pathetic.
Pathetic? What are you talking about?
情けない？
何の話だい
When Jake appears before us,
ジェイクが目の前に現れたとき
I don't think I'll be able to control myself.
自分を抑える自信がないんです
ああ〜 余計な心配してんじゃねえよ
Quit worrying. I've got you covered.
俺に任せとけ
たまには誰かを頼ってみるってのも
Relying on others isn't such a bad thing, you know?
悪くねえぞ
Hey, Kotetsu, Barnaby!
おい 虎徹 バーナビー
おっ…
We've got trouble!
マズいことになった
Citizens of Stern Bild...
シュテルンビルト市民諸君
まずは釈放ありがとう
First off, thank you for releasing me. I am now a free man.
これで俺も晴れて自由の身だ
んん…
ジェイク
Jake!
ハハッ 知らなかったんだよ〜
I had no idea that I was released
俺の釈放と
お前らクソ人間どもの命が
in exchange for the lives of you human garbage.
天秤に かけられてたなんて
Which is why I decided... not to release the hostages!
だからよ とりあえず人質は…
解放しないことに決めたわ〜
ああ…
おい　なんだよ それ…
What is he saying?
In other words, your lives will remain in the palm of my hand.
引き続き お前らの命は
俺の手の中に
置かせてもらうってことだ
After all, you'll do anything I want, right?
だって今なら俺の言うことを
何でも聞いてくれちゃうんだろう？
What should I make you do? Well, until later.
何しよっかな〜
じゃ また
んん…
ああ…
Origami is still safe. Damn it, how long is this going to take?!
折紙は無事か
まったく いつまで
ウロウロしてやがるんだい
んん… んん…
ちょっとマーベリックさん
Mr. Maverick, what's going on?! Mr. Maverick!
マーベリックさん！
We expected this would happen. Our plan is going just fine.
これも想定の範囲内です
作戦に支障はありません
If our spy, Origami Cyclone,
潜入した折紙サイクロンが
パワードスーツを操っている方法さえ
解明してくれれば
tells us how to control the powered exosuits,
we'll have a course of action.
打つ手は いくらでもあります
But how do we explain this to the people?
しっ… しかし 市民には
何と説明したらいいんですか？
We can't reveal this plan to the public. What should we do?
だ… だ… だって
作戦のことは公にはできないわけですし
一体 どうすれ…
I have a plan.
私に考えがあります
What's the meaning of this?
どういうことですか？
一体 どんな交渉したんですか？
What kind of bargain did you make?
Explain this to the people!
市民に説明を！
Give us an answer!
答えてください
お答えください
Give us an answer!
私からは答えられない
I cannot give you an answer!
Mr. Maverick is handling everything.
すべてはマーベリック氏に一任してある
Are you avoiding responsibility?
責任逃れですか？
How can you call yourself our mayor?
それでも あんた市長か！
That's not it. He's going to hold an interview afterwards.
そうじゃない
彼が このあと会見を開くんだから
それで いいじゃないか
Isn't that good enough?
ちょっと待ってください！
Hold on a moment!
Yes. At two o'clock,
ええ では予定どおり14時に
I will explain things to the people just as we have planned.
私の口から 市民に
説明させていただきます
Did you want to see me, sir?
お呼びでしょうか？
市民の皆様に
There is something I must tell all of you.
お伝えしなければならないことが
あります
ご存じのとおり シュテルンビルトは
As you all know, Stern Bild is in the midst of a terrorist attack.
いまだテロの危機に直面しております
ただ市民の皆様の命を最優先した
市長の決断は最善であり
The mayor has decided that your lives take top priority,
and has acted accordingly.
間違っていないと私は考えています
I do not think he is mistaken.
その結果が これかよ
And this is the result?
そうだよ
I'm sure you are dissatisfied with the situation.
いろいろと ご不満はあるでしょう
But I ask you. Shouldn't that anger be directed towards
しかし まず憎むべきはウロボロス
Ouroboros, and that cowardly terrorist, Jake Martinez?
いや ひきょうなテロリスト
ジェイク・マルチネスなのでは
ないでしょうか
There is a Hero
そして 今
静かに闘志を燃やす男がいます
who is waiting patiently to fight these terrorists.
And I think now is the time to reveal
私は今こそ明かすべきだと考えました
why he chose to become a Hero.
彼が なぜヒーローになったのか
Barnaby?
バーナビー？
And why he is the only one who is fighting under his real name.
そして なぜ彼だけが唯一
本名で戦い続けているのかも
ああ…
Reveal my past to the public?
僕の過去を？
Yes. This isn't your problem alone anymore, Barnaby.
ああ
今や もう
君ひとりの問題じゃないんだ
バーナビー
But what about Barnaby's feelings?
けど バーナビーの気持ちってもんが
わかってる
I know.
But right now, the people need the courage and the spirit
だが 今 市民にとって必要なのは
一丸となってテロに立ち向かう勇気
to stand up against those terrorists.
そして団結なんだ
If you share your thoughts with them,
君の思いが伝われば
彼らは きっと奮い立つ
they will surely be inspired.
頼む！　力を貸してほしい
Please, we need your help!
んん…
その忌まわしい惨劇を経て
After that terrible tragedy, he became a Hero and said that
やがてヒーローとなった彼は
he wanted to go by the name "Barnaby Brooks, Jr."
バーナビー・ブルックスJr.と
名乗りたいと申し出ました
Taking on his father's name, "Barnaby Brooks," was his way
殺された父の名である
バーナビー・ブルックスを継ぐこと
of declaring war against the man who killed his parents!
それは彼なりの
犯人への宣戦布告でもあったのです
Is that for real?
まじかよ
So that's why he shows his face.
だから素顔を見せていたのね
His father's name, huh?
親父の名前か〜
And now, he's finally found that man—
そして今ようやく突き止めたのです
the wretched man whom he saw murder his parents
20年前 たった４歳だった
バーナビーの目の前で
両親を殺害した憎むべき犯罪者
twenty years ago, when he was just four years old.
That man is Jake Martinez!
その男こそがジェイクなのです
バーナビーの怒りは市民の皆様と同じ
Barnaby is just as angry as all of you.
いや それ以上です
No, he is even angrier.
“彼のすべては
このときのためにあった”と言っても
It is no exaggeration to say that everything he has done
in his life has been done in anticipation of this moment.
過言ではありません
バーナビーさん
その話は事実なんですか？
Mr. Brooks, is that true?
あっ…
Yes, it is all true.
ええ すべては事実です
I will capture Jake and save this city
ですから
必ず この手でジェイクを捕まえ
テロの脅威から
この町を救ってみせます
from the threat of terrorists!
Yeah!
We're counting on you, Barnaby!
頼むぞ バーナビー
Go get him!
This should get things exciting again.
これで また盛り上がるわね
んん…
あいつ そんな過去が
I never knew he had that kind of past.
それで あんなに必死だったんだ
So that's why he was so desperate.
彼のためにも
必ずジェイクを捕まえようじゃないか！
Let's catch Jake for his sake as well!
あっ…
僕です
It's me.
折紙か？
Origami?
Yes. I've finally gotten inside Jake's hideout.
ええ
今ようやく
ジェイクのアジトに潜入しました
おお
よくやった　やったぞ よく！
Good job! And a job done good!
ただ これからが本番です
But now comes the hard part.
I'm going to look into the secret behind those powered exosuits.
パワードスーツの秘密 探りますね
あんま無理しないでよ 折紙
Don't over do yourself, Origami.
無事に帰ってきたら キスしてあげる
If you come back safely, I'll give you a kiss.
では また連絡します
I'll talk to you later.
ちょっと！　もう〜！
Wait! Jeez...
いよいよ俺たちの出番も近いな
Guess it's time for us to get ready. Right, Kotetsu?
虎徹
ああ
Yeah.
すべては これからだ
This is where it all starts.
僕が消え 遠い未来で
boku ga kie tooi mirai de kaseki ni nattara
When I die and become a fossil in the far future,
化石になったら
人は僕に何を見るだろう
hito wa boku ni nani wo miru darou?
what will people see me as?
分析して 名を付けて
bunseki shite na wo tsukete kaidoku wo shitemo
They may try to analyze, name, and understand me,
解読をしても
愛した人は僕しか知らない
aishita hito wa boku shika shiranai
but only I will know the person I loved.
ハロー 生きること
HELLO ikiru koto
Hello, existence.
君の他に 君はできない
kimi no hoka ni kimi wa dekinai
Only you alone can live your life.
輝き続ける光った星から
kagayaki tsuzukeru hikatta hoshi kara
From the bright star that continues to shine,
輝き続け 光ったあの空から
kagayaki tsuzuke hikatta ano sora kara
from that bright sky that continues to shine.
僕らは何を感じられるだろう
bokura wa nani wo kanjirareru darou?
What can we feel from it?
奇跡は宇宙だけじゃないよ
kiseki wa uchuu dake janai yo
The universe isn't the only miracle.
輝き続ける光った星から
kagayaki tsuzukeru hikatta hoshi kara
From the bright star that continues to shine,
輝き続け 光ったあの空から
kagayaki tsuzuke hikatta ano sora kara
from that bright sky that continues to shine.
目を閉じたって 閉じきれないよ
me wo tojitatte tojikirenaiyo
You can try to shut your eyes, but you can't shut out your heart.
あの星さえ 持てなかった心
ano hoshi sae motenakatta kokoro
It's something that even the stars did not possess.
ただ これからが本番です
But now comes the hard part.
パワードスーツの秘密 探りますね
I'm going to look into the secret behind those powered exosuits.
あんま無理しないでよ 折紙
Don't over do yourself, Origami.
無事に帰ってきたら キスしてあげる
If you come back safely, I'll give you a kiss.
では また連絡します
I'll talk to you later.
あっ…
どうだ チャックマン
俺の おニューな髪型は？
Hey, Chuckman. What do you think of my new haircut?
あっ？
あっ…とても お似合いだと思います
Uh... It looks very good on you, sir.
だろ〜！　ヒーローみたいだな〜
Doesn't it? It makes me look like a Hero, huh?
いいよな〜 ヒーロー
Heroes are great, aren't they? They're so cool.
かっこいいね〜
お前さ〜 ヒーローって どう思う？
Say, what do you think of Heroes?
あのレジェンドの豚野郎が
死んだかと思えば いつの間にか
Right after that pig, Legend, died,
どいつも こいつも ＮＥＸＴのくせに
all those NEXT started to side with the humans.
人間どもに肩入れしやがって
サイコーじゃねえか〜
It's awesome!
んん…
サイコーに邪魔くせえよな
How awesome for them to be such a nuisance, you know?
俺たちの理想って
そういうもんじゃねえよな
That's not what we want, is it?
おお ビンゴ！
Ah, bingo!
おい チャックマン
こいつをどう思う？
Hey, Chuckman, what do you think of him?
んん…
お前 ＮＥＸＴになって
この能力が手に入ったら うれしいか？
If you became a NEXT, would you like this ability?
どうだ〜？
あっ？
What do you think?
えっ ええ… まあ…
Uh, yes... I think.
あっ…
バカみてえな格好してるけど
He looks silly, but I think he's useful.
俺は こいつ使えると思うんだわ
いや！
こいつを使わない手はねえな〜
In fact, there's no way I would waste a power like his.
例えば どんなときかって〜？
When would I use him?
そうだな〜
Well, don't you think he'd be the perfect spy?
“潜入〜！”とか
打ってつけだと思わねえか〜？
おい どうした？
Hey, what's wrong?
すごい汗でござるよ
You're sweating a lot.
どうも！　TIGER ＆ BUNNYの
ハンバーガーは
一度 潰してから食べるほう 虎徹です
Hi! I'm Kotetsu, the member of "Tiger & Bunny,"
who squashes his burgers before he eats them!
ついに たどり着いたバーナビーの仇
We've finally come face to face with the guy
この野郎 何て奴だ
who killed Barnaby's parents!
次回　TIGER ＆ BUNNY
Damn, this bastard is strong!
テイク ヘッヘッ ヘイド オ…
Next time on TIGER & BUNNY:
とりあえずヤバい
Anyway, this is bad!